<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Tamas&#39; blog for sports analytics and other data topics</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Tamas&#39; blog for sports analytics and other data topics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 06:42:21 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Did DeAndre Jordan Learn How to Shoot Free Throws?</title>
      <link>/blog/did-deandre-jordan-learn-how-to-shoot-free-throws/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/did-deandre-jordan-learn-how-to-shoot-free-throws/</guid>
      <description>At the time of writing this DeAndre Jordan has made 82% of his free throws (on 34 attempts) in the 2018-19 NBA regular season.
For those who did not pay attention, this might not raise many eyebrows. However, we are talking about one of the worst free throw shooters in the NBA, achieving a career 45% from the line while taking 100+ attempts every year since his rookie season.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russell Westbrook And The Value of a Triple-Double</title>
      <link>/blog/russell-westbrook-and-the-value-of-a-triple-double/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/russell-westbrook-and-the-value-of-a-triple-double/</guid>
      <description>Russell Westbrook is unquestionably one of the most fun players to watch in the NBA.
Personally, he’s my favorite. His energy and raw talent can light up the court and fans around the World, with spectacular moves like this:
Russ is also known to frequently produce triple-doubles, a measure of his superhuman ability to perform in multiple areas of the game. Not everyone is into these triple-doubles though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Was this the closest race for the NBA Playoffs ever?</title>
      <link>/blog/nba-playoff-race-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/nba-playoff-race-2018/</guid>
      <description>This question probably got decided the second the Denver Nuggets took the Timberwolves to overtime for the 8th and last playoff-worthy position in West, on the last day of the regular season… but that should not stop us from looking back at what has transpired at finish line before the Playoffs with the help of some data.Teams have moved up and down the standings like never beforeTeams have switched positions a lot during the run-up of this season’s finale… and I wanted to see how abnormal this was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TBBT (Tidy)Text analysis 2 - Sentiments across genders</title>
      <link>/blog/tbbt-genders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tbbt-genders/</guid>
      <description>My inspiration to write this post was Julia Silge’s “She giggles, he gallops” on pudding.cool.
Julia examines 2,000 film scripts, to uncover certain “gender bias” - notably, she compared what are the most frequent words following “he” and “she” in the scripts.
I’m going to apply the same idea to the subtitle data of the TV series ‘The Big Bang Theory’.
Just before we dive in - this post is the second in my “TBBT (Tidy)Text analysis” mini-series, if interested, you can find the first one here, in which I look at the relation between average IMDB scores of episodes and dominating character “mentions”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TBBT (Tidy)Text analysis 1 - IMDB scores and character mentions</title>
      <link>/blog/tbbt-imdb-score-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tbbt-imdb-score-regression/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the first post in my ‘The Big Bang Theory (Tidy)Text analysis’ mini-series, and with that, to the very first post on my blog!
Recently I was taking a class on ‘Data Science on Unstructured Text Data’, for which our final project was to create a tidyverse text analysis of any topic of our choice.
While originally I set my sight on some deep topics, I ended up with something lighter this time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>