<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Text Analysis on Tamas&#39; blog for sports analytics and more data topics</title>
    <link>/categories/text-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Text Analysis on Tamas&#39; blog for sports analytics and more data topics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/text-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TBBT (Tidy)Text analysis 2 - Sentiments across genders</title>
      <link>/blog/tbbt-genders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tbbt-genders/</guid>
      <description>My inspiration to write this post was Julia Silge’s “She giggles, he gallops” on pudding.cool.
Julia examines 2,000 film scripts, to uncover certain “gender bias” - notably, she compared what are the most frequent words following “he” and “she” in the scripts.
I’m going to apply the same idea to the subtitle data of the TV series ‘The Big Bang Theory’.
Just before we dive in - this post is the second in my “TBBT (Tidy)Text analysis” mini-series, if interested, you can find the first one here, in which I look at the relation between average IMDB scores of episodes and dominating character “mentions”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TBBT (Tidy)Text analysis 1 - IMDB scores and character mentions</title>
      <link>/blog/tbbt-imdb-score-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tbbt-imdb-score-regression/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the first post in my ‘The Big Bang Theory (Tidy)Text analysis’ mini-series, and with that, to the very first post on my blog!
Recently I was taking a class on ‘Data Science on Unstructured Text Data’, for which our final project was to create a tidyverse text analysis of any topic of our choice.
While originally I set my sight on some deep topics, I ended up with something lighter this time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>